

Nikhil Bangar

AWS Dev-ops Engineer

nikhilbangar8@gmail.com

+91-8483955493

PUNE C

nikhilbangar8.github.io/profile/

linkedin.com/in/nikhil-bangar-21b229146 in

github.com/nikhilbangar8 🌎

A certified Cloud Devops Engineer with multiple years of experiance in handling and Developing Cloud Applications. Worked in a multicloud environment, maintaining application in reliable and optimal Environment. Also worked in a plaform team to build up the automation tools for operations team to handle the cloud infrastructure.

Pune

Pune

WORK EXPERIENCE

Platform Engineer

Cloudreach

03/2021 - Present

Achievements/Tasks

- Worked in platform Team to support and maintain Internally Developed tools for Cloud Infrastructure Services
- Developement of Automation Platform Workflows (Stackstorm) which involves integration with cloud service providers, Ansible and Servicenow, Vault Integration.
- Resolution of the IAAC errors in for 30+ Customers
- Developing Automation Workflows for Automatic Incident Investigation and Resolution

Devops Engineer

Wipro

11/2018 - 02/2021

Worked for UK Based Insurance Company as AWS DEVOPS Engineer

Achievements/Tasks

- The building of AMIs for monthly Release cycle for Compliance, Vulnerability Resolution, Addition of Infra stacks as per client Requirement using Terraform, Packer, and Puppet.
- Maintaining and Creating New Jenkins Pipelines for Deployments of New Package, Infrastructure Deployment and AMI Build.
- Maintenance of AWS Infra for a variety of applications [20+] involving 24*7 Web Servers, Databases on RDS, SQL Databases on EC2, Analytics Applications, Lambda functions.
- Performing Blue-Green Deployments in Non-Prod and Production Environments.
- Resolution of Errors in AWS Deployment Pipelines. Optimizing Infrastructure for Cost Reduction and Better performance.
- Leading Cost Optimization Strategies and Implementing it for All Applications supported by Team.
- Resolution of Production Incidents and managing them. Creation of server management scripts.
- Resolution of various vulnerabilities in Windows and RHEL Servers, Patching of Pet Servers.
- Performing Disaster Recovery Activities for web and DB applications in Non-Production and Production Environments.

SKILLS



ACHIEVEMENTS

BU Awards - 2020 - May

Inspiring Performance [Extraordinary Commitment] - 2019 - DECEMBER

Inspiring Performance [Achievement Orientation] - 2019 - JULY

Round of Applause [Achievement Orientation] - 2019 - JUNE

You Made a Difference - 2019 - MAY

Round of Applause - 2019 - APRIL

CERTIFICATES

AWS Certified Devops Engineer Proffesional (07/2021 - 07/2024)

AWS Certified Solutions Architect-Associate (06/2020 - 06/2023)

AWS Certified Developer Associcate (07/2020 - 07/2023)

AWS Certified Sysops Administrator Associcate (07/2020 - 07/2020)

Azure Fundamentals (AZ-900) (06/2020 - Present)

WORK EXPERIENCE

AWS Developer

Wipro

02/2019 - 03/2021

Performing Value Add's for Better Management of AWS Infrastructure

Achievements/Tasks

- Aws Optimiser Tool:A Analytics tool to monitor AWS accounts to find idle and underperforming resources for cost optimisation. Displaying the all data to all stake holders to a dashboard. This was developed with AWS Boto3 + Django Framework, HTML + JS (ChartJS and Bootstrap)
- Email Scrapper Alert Dashboard:Development of Analytics Tool.Programmatic reading Email for alerts, and classifying each email alert according to Environment, Type of alert, Criticality of application. Displaying the status of alerts on the Web-page hosted on the Django server. The back-end is developed in Python and front-end in HTML and JS(charts.js)
- JIRA Creator (Windows Application): Development of Windows Application for Creation of various JIRA tickets for Better formatting and Reduction of time. The Application was Developed using Python (TKinter and JIRA RestAPI)
- JIRA Review System: Development of Web ApplicationReview System for improving the Quality of the JIRA (Evaluation of ticket for correct details). The application was developed in HTML, JS, Python.
- Incident and Changes Dashboards: Development of Dashboards for Open Incidents and Changes assigned to a team with required details using Assyst Rest API, HTML, JS, Python, Rest API Creation of Scripts for Optimization activities.

Developer

Wipro

07/2018 - 11/2018

Worked for Japanese Optical Instrument MFG company as .net / C++ developer

Achievements/Tasks

- Modification for the logs segregation feature for the logger application developed in C++ .NET Application.
- Resolution of Bugs for Multi threading part for Logger Application.
- Manual Testing and Documentation for C# application used for Image Processing Desktop Application.

EDUCATION

O Bachelor of Engineering

MIT College of Engineering, Pune

08/2014 - 06/2018

Projects

- Creation of small-scaled working Model Adaptive Cruise Control System for 4-Wheel Vehicle. The Model was built in Arduino Mega. Coded in C++.
- The part was College Robotics Team as Engineer, Tech Lead, and Mentor in 2nd, 3rd, and 4th of the college. Built various Robots and represented college team for 3 years in National Level Robotics Competition. Financing and Team management in 3rd year.
- Building of Robots for ROBOCON 2016,2017,2018. Frisbee throwing Robot, Badminton playing Robot, ECO Robot etc.

SKILLS

Pune

Pune

72%

ORGANIZATIONS

Center for Robotics Excellence - MITCOE, Pune (08/2015 - 04/2018)

Research and Developement Engineer

College Go-Cart Racing Team (07/2017 - 11/2017)

Manufacturing Consultant

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hind

Full Professional Proficiency

Marathi

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

INTERESTS

Reading

Swimming